Guide to the Hermann John Weigand Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Additional material, 1906-2005; Accession 2017-M-0060
  - Writings
    - "The Message of Meredith's Egoist" notebook, 1913-03-13 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - "Meyer in der Heidze", 1912-02-22 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Milton essay, 1912-12-07 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - "The Modern Ibsen", 1952 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - "Monatsheffe fur Deutschen Unterricht" (multiple volumes), 1939-1961 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - "The Necessity of Determinism" notebook, 1913-06-04 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - "The New Laocoon, by Irving Babbitt Houghton Mifflin Company" notebook, 1911 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Nur Order Nie?, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Papers, 1964-1967 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - "Paul Hegel - Die Novelle" notebook, 1912-03-16 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - "Peter Schlemihl", Undated (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - "Plato's Gorgias" notebook, Undated (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - "Principle versus Program" booklet, 1914-03-18 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Reprints, Undated (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - "Review: Goethe's Faust as a Renaissance Man (Harold Jantz)", 1952-10 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - "Rilkes Romische Sarkophage", 1961 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Scandinavian 2 notebook, 1912-03-02 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - "Schiller and the Romantic School" notebook, Undated (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - "Some Aspects of Goethe's Relation to Winchelmaur" notebook, Undated (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - "Spiritual Therapy in Wolfram's Parzival", 1977 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - "Spiritual Therapy in Wolfram's Parzival", 1978-11 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Starr's "Scheinem Elreiter" notebook, 1912-01-22 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - "Stutzer der Gesellschaft" notebook, 1912-05-21 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - "Surveys and Soundings in European Literature", 1966 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - "Thomas Mann and Goethe: A Supplement and a Correction", 1956-11 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - "Thomas Mann zum Gedachtnis", 1956 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - "Thomas Mann's Novel der Zauberberg" (with notes enclosed), 1933-1964 (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - "Thoughts on the Passing of Thomas Mann", 1956 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - "The Two and Seventy Languages of the World", Undated (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Undergraduate papers, 1917 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Volkelt notebook, Undated (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - "Wandrers Sturmlied: Once More with Obiter Dicta", Undated (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - "The Will: Its Meaning in the Life of the Individual and the Social Whole" notebook, 1914-04-24 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - "Wolfram's Parzival" book, 1969 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Writings published in German Quarterly, 1965, 1985; 1985 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - "The Yale University Library Gazette", 1958-10 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - "Zu Kleists' Katchen von Heilbronn", 1967 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Personal papers
    - "A Tribute to Hermann Weigand", 1982 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Certifikat der tax-und treuhandstelle, 1930-08 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Copy of photograph and ancestry records, Undated (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Death certificate and stationery paper, 1985-12-12 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Excerpt from "A Tribute to Hermann Weigand", Undated (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Excerpt from diary, 1951 (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Excerpt from diary on "The Case Against Thomas Mann" in "The American Mercury", 1951-10 (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - German Order of Merit award, 1967 (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Hermann J. Weigand Fellowship booklets (including eulogies), 1986 (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Hermann J. Weigand obituaries, 1985-1986 (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - In memoriam tributes, 1985 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Memorial service notices, 1985 (Box 14, Folder 2)
      Includes photographs of Hermann Weigand.
    - Obituary clipping from the New York Times, 1985-09-07 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Vitae, 1954-1979 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Program files
    - "A Tribute to Hermann Weigand" event schedule, 1982-11-17 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Amherst College lecture poster, 1977-03-10 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Asheville Symphony Orchestra and Chorus, 1975 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Broch Conference, 2001 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Deutsche Gedichte, 1961 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - "Goethe and the World of Music" keynote, 1947 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Gruppe 47 at Princeton University, 1966-04 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Hamlin lecture - packet of songs, Undated (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Lecture posters, 1971-10 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - University of Colorado commencement, 1968 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Photographs and audiovisual material
    - Photographs
      - "Happy Birthday '64 to Mary Weigand" album, 1963-11 (Box 14, Folder 15)
      - Hermann Weigand, 1913-1916, 1926-1927 (Box 14, Folder 16)
      - Hermann Weigand, 1938-1975 (Box 14, Folder 17)
        Includes film strips and negatives.
      - Hermann Weigand and family, 1924-1948 (Box 14, Folder 18)
      - Hermann Weigand and family, including 'Father Time shot', Undated (Box 14, Folder 19)
      - Hermann Weigand and Frances Weigand, 1916, 1929, 1937, Undated (Box 14, Folder 20)
        Includes negatives.
      - Hermann Weigand and unidentified children, possibly his grandchildren, Undated (Box 14, Folder 21)
      - Hermann Weigand and receipts, 1992 (Box 14, Folder 22)
      - Portrait photographs, Undated (Box 14, Folder 23)
      - Portrait photographs from class at University of California, Berkeley, 1946, 1978?; 1978 (Box 14, Folder 24)
      - Small album and photograph of unidentified woman, Undated (Box 14, Folder 25)
      - Three unidentified people at a waterfall, Undated (Box 14, Folder 26)
      - Unidentified couple, Undated (Box 14, Folder 27)
    - Audiocassettes
      Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Researchers wishing to obtain an additional copy of non-commercially produced items for their personal use should consult the ordering reproductions information on the Manuscripts and Archives web site.
      - Mary's reading of "Das Bett", Undated; 1 (Box 16)
      - Reading of "Spiritual Therapy in Wolfram's Parzival", 1977; 1 (Box 17)
      - Unidentified recording, Undated; 1 (Box 18)